Jorge Romo

Senior Frontend Developer

romo.jorge126@gmail.com | (440) 508-6823

jorge-romo.github.io | linkedin.com/in/jorge-romo-50261b240

412 Covington Ave, Odessa, TX 79763

Software developer with 6+ years of experience with a passion for both personal growth and web development. Detail-oriented, organized, and meticulous employee. Quick learner, strong reasoning, and problem-solving skills. Works at a fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Ready to apply my passion for coding to a talented engineering team to develop quality solutions.

EDUCATION

University of North Texas

Denton, TX

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

May 2018

SKILLS

React, Next.js, Angular, Node.js, Javascript, Typescript, GraphQL, Jest, Redux, Storybook, TailwindCSS, Material UI, SASS, Git, CI/CD, AWS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Upwork

Odessa, TX (Remote)

Freelance Software Developer

November 2024 - Present

- Demonstrated excellent communication and collaboration skills, working closely with clients to understand their needs and expectations, and providing regular updates and feedback.
- Showcased creativity and problem-solving abilities, using various WordPress features and plugins to create customized and responsive websites that met the clients' specifications and goals.

Skills: React.js, Angular, Node.js, WordPress, Javascript, Typescript, AWS, Git

Hitachi Vantara LLC (Hitachi Digital Service)

Dallas, TX (Hybrid)

Sr. Frontend Engineer

March 2023 - November 2024

- Mentored 3+ new recruits, provided onboarding orientation seminars and conducted group and individual training sessions.
- Built a call center web app using Amazon Connect and Amazon QuickSight in collaboration with 3 teammates.
- Built and architected a library for rendering dynamic forms, enhancing development speed.
- Worked with the core team to develop a UI library containing atomic UI components and utilities, adhering to UX/UI design principles.

Skills: React.js, Angular, Node.js, Typescript, AWS, Git

Photon Interactive Private Limited

Dallas, TX (On-site)

Frontend Developer

September 2018 - March 2023

- Maintained site functionality with team updating pull requests and grooming program daily.
- Tasked with developing an automated scraper tool for extraction of data.
- Provided developers with an initialized codebase to speed up the development process.
- Produced UX/UI designs using React to production while working with the QA testing to improve program performance features.

Skills: React.js, Node.js, Javascript, Git

PROJECTS

Foundry (Solid Design) - BYND LLC

2023

https://idg-dev-345810.nw.r.appspot.com

Sr. Frontend Developer

Foundry is a component foundation project designed to deliver a scalable, reusable, and efficient library of UI components. The project focuses on enhancing Foundry's web page elements. I collaborated with a team of developers to create and refine various components, including text fields, radio buttons, and more, ensuring optimal functionality and usability.

Skills: Typescript, SASS, Jest, Storybook

PassionList - PassionList

2019

http://dev.passionlist.com

Javascript Developer

PassionList is a curated platform for car enthusiasts, showcasing the most intriguing cars for sale daily. It's more than just a marketplace—it's a community for those passionate about cars. I collaborated with a team of developers to design and implement the company's main webpage using the JavaScript stack, delivering a seamless and engaging user experience.

Skills: Javascript, React, Express.js, MongoDB, Node.js, SCSS, Jest, Redux, Redux Saga